import questionImage from "../assets/question-bucket-2.svg";
export const questions = {
    bucket_name: "Impacts of climate change",
    image: questionImage,
    questions: [{
        question: "True or false: Temperatures in Southeast Asia has exceeded 40ºC in 2023.",
        options: ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
        answer: "TRUE",
        followup_text: "The heat wave in April 2023 saw extreme temperatures of 46ºC in Vietnam and Laos.",
        source: "https://edition.cnn.com/2023/06/06/asia/southeast-asia-heat-wave-humidity-climate-intl-hnk-dst-scn-dg/index.html"
    },
    {
        question: "What impacts will climate change have on Southeast Asia?",
        options: ["Heat waves", "Floods and droughts",	"Rising sea levels", "All of the above"],
        answer: "All of the above",
        followup_text: "Southeast Asia is facing the threat of heat waves, floods, droughts and rising sea levels as a result of climate change.",
        source: "https://www.usaid.gov/asia-regional/fact-sheets/confronting-climate-crisis-southeast-asia-regional-approach#:~:text=Southeast%20Asia%20is%20one%20of,intense%20and%20unpredictable%20weather%20events."
    },{
        question: "True or false: A desert is growing in Vietnam as a result of climate change.",
        options: ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
        answer: "TRUE",
        followup_text: "The desert in the Binh Thuan province of Vietnam is expected to grow to 32% by 2050.",
        source: "https://nhess.copernicus.org/articles/19/2325/2019/nhess-19-2325-2019.html#:~:text=The%20area%20at%20risk%20of,climate%20change%20and%20population%20growth."
    },{
        question: "Which animal in Asia is threatened by climate change AND has a movie character named after it?",
        options: ["Bumblebee", "T-Rex", "Dodo Bird"],
        answer: "Bumblebee",
        followup_text: "Bumblebees in East Asia are being threatened by climate change. Bumblebee is also the name of a Transformers character.",
        source: "https://news.cgtn.com/news/3d3d774d7763544e33457a6333566d54/index.html"
    },{
        question: "China, Indonesia, Philippines, Thailand and Vietnam produce half of the world's...",
        options: ["Supply of rice", "Plastic waste in the oceans"],
        answer: "Plastic waste in the oceans",
        followup_text: "China, Indonesia, Philippines, Thailand and Vietnam produce half of all plastic waste in the oceans.",
        source: "https://borgenproject.org/10-facts-about-plastic-waste-in-southeast-asia/"
    },{
        question: "True or false: Supermarkets in Thailand are no longer giving out plastic bags.",
        options: ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
        answer: "TRUE",
        followup_text: "Thailand has banned single-use plastic bags at major stores since 2020.",
        source: "https://www.reuters.com/article/us-thailand-environment-plastic-idUSKBN1Z01TR"
    },
    {
        question: "True or false: Supermarkets in Singapore are no longer giving out plastic bags.",
        options: ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
        answer: "FALSE",
        followup_text: "Single-use plastic bags are still used in Singapore supermarkets. However, they are chargeable.",
        source: "https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-07-03/singapore-supermarkets-start-charging-for-plastic-bags"
    },{
        question: "True or false: Buildings in Southeast Asia account for 25% of its carbon dioxide emissions.",
        options: ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
        answer: "TRUE",
        followup_text: "Buildings account for close to 25% of Southeast Asia's energy-related carbon dioxide emissions.",
        source: "https://www.iea.org/reports/roadmap-for-energy-efficient-buildings-and-construction-in-the-association-of-southeast-asian-nations#:~:text=The%20buildings%20sector%20plays%20a,energy%2Drelated%20CO2%20emissions."
    },{
        question: "Which Southeast Asian country has announced plans to stop selling fossil fuel vehicles?",
        options: ["Singapore	Thailand", "Indonesia",	"All of the above"],
        answer: "All of the above",
        followup_text: "Singapore was the first to announce a ban on the sale of fossil fuel vehicles. Thailand and Indonesia have also made similar announcements.",
        source: "https://scandasia.com/scandinavian-and-asian-countries-final-fossil-fuel-dates/"
    },{
        question: "Air pollution in Southeast Asia is mostly caused by...",
        options: ["Industry emissions", "Power generation", "Vehicle emissions", "All of the above"],
        answer: "All of the above",
        followup_text: "Air quality levels in Southeast Asia were badly affected by industry emissions, power generation and vehicle emissions in 2022.",
        source: "https://www.channelnewsasia.com/asia/air-quality-pollution-iqair-southeast-asia-3348551"
    }]
}

    








